# Ping-Chun Lin

Seattle, WA ☐ contact@pingchunlin.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/pingchunlin 🗘 PingChunLin

A research and data scientist with four years of experience in **machine learning**, **computer vision**, and **technical projects**. Motivated to transition from academia to take on applied challenges. Strong ability to think big, innovate, and quickly master new technical fields.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **University of Washington**

Sep 2019 - present

Graduate Researcher funded by the Simons Foundation

Seattle, WA

- Developed a novel data-driven approach (linear/lasso regression) to predict key environmental parameters. Reduced analysis time compared to counterpart methods from hours to <10 seconds, enabling rapid application across multiple studies.
- Conducted statistical analysis of previously unused data features from experimental datasets, unlocking new insights and strategies for predictive modeling that led to a research publication.

#### Global Innovation Fund at UW

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

Machine Learning Developer

Seattle, WA

- Developed a computer vision pipeline for labeling instances on satellite images using R-CNNs (Detectron2) with high accuracy, reducing 90% of the processing time and cost for manual labor.
- Co-authored a report to stakeholders about the performance of the model and utilizing machine learning techniques for climate change research.

## University of Washington

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019

Research Assistant funded by NASA Habitable Worlds

Seattle, WA

- Developed an application that analyzes feature changes in 6000 images from a time-lapse video and satellite imagery, contributing to Earth and Mars research, with published results in a peer-reviewed journal.
- · Co-developed a hydrology model and visualized the output using a digital elevation model in ArcGIS.

# PROJECTS AND LEADERSHIP

**Software Developer** 

Sep 2022 - Dec 2022

microSWIFT Team, collaboration with UW Applied Physics Lab

Seattle, WA

Co-developed a Rasberry Pi quality control pipeline and produced an open-source package on PyPI for the collaborators
and enthusiasts to access the research data from wave buoys.

Lab Instructor Jan 2021 - Present

University of Washington

Seattle, WA

Seattle, WA

- Led experiments, graded coursework, and answered questions from 120+ students.
- · Mentored five students and designed three remote-friendly lab experiments for effective virtual learning experiences.

# Executive Committee Chair

Jan 2021 - Jun 2023

- UW Taiwanese Graduate Student Association
- Led a team of 20+ members to organize events annually for graduate students and early-career professionals, including social events with the local community and career workshops with alumni.
- Deployed task management tools and a membership database for efficient remote operations of the organization.

### **SKILLS**

- Programming languages: Python (pandas, Tensorflow, PyTorch, sklearn, OpenCV, pillow, GDAL), SQL, Java
- Numerical modeling: Numerical models, computer vision, machine learning, time series
- Other Tools: Version control (Git), geospatial data analysis (ArcGIS, Google Earth Engine), Unix/Linux, ETL, Excel
- Technical Skills: Technical writing, A/B testing, statistics, data analysis, data manipulation, data visualization

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Washington**

Present

Ph.D. in Data Science, Earth and Space Sciences and Astrobiology

• Relevant Courses: Database Systems, Complex Systems, Applied Linear Algebra, Software Development Bachelor of Science in Geophysics

2019

· Minor: Applied Mathematics

Other Certifications: Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera), Large Language Models (Coursera)